ALL CHARACTERS, LOCATIONS
AND INCIDENTS IN THIS ARE FICTITIOUS
JUDGE: I will now announce the ruling.
The accused stomped on and kicked
the victim's head and chest multiple times
in front of their child
for the sole reason of being offended,
resulting in the victim's death.
The accused has a history
of being punished for crimes of
a similar manner in the past,
and a heavy sentence is inevitable
for taking an innocent life
over a minor dispute.
However, considering
the fact that there was
no intention to kill,
the fact that he tried his best
to settle with the victim's family,
and the fact that he is
being treated for mental illness,
and taking into account his deep remorse
and reflection on the crime,
I sentence him
to three and a half years in prison.
(GAVEL BANGING)
Little shit.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(YELPS)
(GROANING)
(SOBS)
(SCOFFS)
(SOBBING)
(CRYING) Wake up!
Mom!
12 YEARS LATER
(SIREN WAILING IN DISTANCE)
(VEHICLE APPROACHING)
-(ENGINE STOPS)
-(TIRES SCREECH)
Hello.
-(GROANS)
-You son of a bitch!
How dare you call the cops on me.
-How dare you!
-Why are you doing this?
You son of a bitch.
Did you think I'd never find you?
Did you think so, you piece of shit?
Come here, you bastard.
-Why are you doing this?
-Are you sorry?
-Yes, I'm sorry.
-You should be, you shit.
-I'm sorry.
-Yes, you should be sorry!
You son of a bitch.
You should be.
So you should be taught a lesson.
Call the cops on me.
You piece of shit.
You fucking loser.
Because of you, I had to go
to the police station over nothing.
You son of a bitch.
God damn it.
What?
What are you looking at,
you pieces of shit?
Call the police.
You. Go ahead
and call the fucking cops on me.
Do it, and I will fucking kill you all!
That piece of shit.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(WHISTLING TUNEFULLY)
(WHISTLING CONTINUES)
(WHISTLING STOPS)
Hey.
Who are you?
Are you following me?
Answer me, you bastard!
Choi Sungsoo, 18 criminal convictions.
How are you roaming freely like this?
How?
I can
because that's what the law decided,
you bastard!
-(GROANING)
-(BOTTLE CLATTERS)
(SCREAMS) God damn it...
Son of a bitch!
-(GROANS)
-You can't be living like this.
My family was ruined because of you.
What kind of law is this?
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
(GROANS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Thank you. (PANTS)
For remaining a piece of shit.
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(SIGHS)
VIGILANTE
Now, this graph shows the arrest rates
for murder cases from 2018 to 2021
based on the crime statistics
of the Supreme Prosecutors' Office.
As you can see, it's odd.
The arrest rates are over 100%.
So how did this happen?
It's because
these statistics include cold cases
we've solved.
If we exclude the cold cases,
from 2012 to 2021,
the average arrest rate for murders
is 98.5%.
-Professor.
-Yes?
What about the rest of the cold cases?
Exactly.
Why haven't they been solved?
Maybe they're already serving time
for other crimes like the Hwaseong Case.
Murder consists
of a significant proportion
of first-time offenders.
But there is
a high possibility
that they're not first-time offenders.
Then what if someone
who committed murder in the past
is lucky enough to be sentenced
for a petty crime?
When they are released...
While there is
no statute of limitations for murder,
it's likely to be a long-term cold case.
In fact, it happens a lot.
It's something you have to keep working on
as a police officer.
Having said that,
write down your opinions on this matter
and submit them by our next class.
Okay? That'll be all.
(ALL MURMUR IN AGREEMENT)
-That'll be all.
-Sorry, guys.
-Let's go!
-ALL: Let's go!
(PANTING)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
Seonwook must not
be feeling himself today.
Didn't he use to be a judoka?
It's not that.
It's that Jiyong is that good.
He's growing at an incredible pace.
Those two can go out in the field
right now.
I know. But let's not show it.
They'll get full of themselves.
(GRUNTING)
MAN: One full point.
(EXHALES)
MIN SEONWOOK, KIM JIYONG
MAN: Bow.
(GRUNTING)
God, that bastard.
SEONPO STATION, UNPROVOKED ATTACK
ARREST WARRANT REJECTED
(GRUNTS) You were so good today.
I learned something new.
I totally let you win.
You may be better than me
at everything else,
but not at judo.
Right. Hey.
That shampooing trick.
You used it at
the National Sports Festival too, right?
Hey, it's good for preventing hair loss
and it smells good.
It's freaking expensive.
(CHUCKLES) I think I can beat you too,
you punk.
(LAUGHS)
By the way, use that expensive shampoo
on me next time.
So that I can be fragrant in the club.
-(LAUGHS)
-Crazy bastard.
-Jiyong.
-Yes?
You should go clubbing with us
before we get appointed.
I can't. You know I'm busy on weekends.
You can't be that busy, you bastard.
What's wrong with you?
I'm sleeping.
She dropped them again.
Ma'am.
Ma'am. Ma'am?
I told you, you have to tie them tighter.
Like this.
Done.
For your trouble.
Thank you.
Oh, wait.
Careful.
YONG GUKBAP RESTAURANT
Kim randomly attacked a stranger near
Seonpo Station on the 27th last month,
and a warrant for his arrest
was reviewed today.
It has been confirmed
that it was rejected.
FEMALE NEWSREADER:
Last month, Kim broke into a house
near Seonpo Station, urinated,
and went on a rampage.
The resident was attacked
while trying to stop him,
and his injuries require
18 weeks to recover.
Kim fled after committing the crime
and was arrested at his house
a week later, on the third.
The court stated that
they rejected the warrant
because Kim was sleeping
and had no intention
to flee or destroy evidence.
The family of An, the victim,
expressed their fear of retaliation,
and citizens are enraged
by the court's decision.
They expressed their anger
questioning whom the law is for.
Kim was held in custody,
and released around 10:00 p.m.
after the warrant was rejected.
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
UNPROVOKED ATTACK NEAR SEONPO STATION.
ARREST WARRANT REJECTED?
"Assaulted homeowner who tried to stop him
from urinating on their property."
"Requires 18 weeks to recover."
"The arrest warrant was rejected."
(DOOR OPENS)
(SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING)
(WOMAN GASPS)
My, my. You still live here?
Why the hell won't you move?
Because you have no money?
Are you that poor?
Because of that bastard,
I even appeared on the news.
It's fucking embarrassing.
What are you looking at, you little shit?
Do you want to die?
Want me to beat you up like your dad?
-(WOMAN YELPS)
-I suddenly want to pee.
I might wet myself. I really need to go.
"Did the law punish them properly?"
(CRASHING)
Who are you, bastard?
The pee got on me, you little...
(GROANING)
You bastard.
You're dead today, you bastard!
Hold on. Stop. God damn it.
-(GROANS)
-Fuck!
DO NOT LITTER
DOCTOR WHO SEXUALLY ASSAULTED VICTIMS AND
FILMED EVERYTHING, STILL SEEING PATIENTS
He put a patient to sleep, raped her,
and even secretly filmed it,
but was sentenced to six months in prison?
He wasn't even stripped
of his license, damn it.
"Was it premeditated?"
Who are you?
I'm doing surgery. Get out.
-What do you want?
-(GROANS)
(GROANS)
(OBJECTS CLATTERING)
Quit being a doctor and find another job.
(SCREAMS IN PAIN)
(SIGHS)
(WRAPPER CRINKLING)
(IN ENGLISH) Good morning.
Hey! I didn't tell you to come in.
(IN KOREAN) I investigated this.
Why don't you take a look?
-What's that?
-A scoop.
What? Are you kidding? This is
just a collection of violent crimes.
Do you know what those cases
have in common?
It's that the perpetrators
have all been released
because of the court's absurd rulings.
What do you mean?
The Seonpo Station unprovoked attacker
whose arrest warrant was rejected.
The doctor who kept his license
after habitually
sexually assaulting his patients.
The man who got two years in prison
for killing and burying his girlfriend.
The person who got probation for running
over his friend over owed money.
Those cases were all covered in the news
and evoked outrage.
"The law is not protecting
the citizens properly."
"The law is on the perpetrators' side."
Because of loopholes in the law,
perpetrators are being released
without being punished properly,
and someone is making them pay
for what they did.
Interesting.
Why don't you try writing a script?
Can't you see what the public wants?
An era that's cold to the weak
and lenient with those with connections.
The law's failing
to punish them accordingly,
and someone's punishing them
with violence.
People want a dark hero like this person.
But isn't it likely to be a coincidence?
All right, then.
You don't seem to get what I'm saying.
So I'll just go to
another broadcasting company.
Ms. Choi, wait.
What's the rush? After we verify it...
Keep verifying it, then.
I'll take it to a company
who's interested.
Wait.
(CLEARS THROAT) So what will the title be?
"Vigilante."
YOUNG ONE, LET JUSTICE FLOW LIKE A RIVER
-Nice shot!
(WHOOPING)
-One, two, three!
-(CHEERING)
Maybe they keep committing crimes
because they only get two to three years
even after destroying someone's life.
I think that's somewhat off the point.
I can raise the issue of it, can't I?
But who are you to do it?
Seonwook.
Let's write it with the idea
that they all paid for their crimes.
Or we'll get more homework like last time.
I mean, how will we reform them
when they don't even repent?
Then what do we do?
Should the police retaliate?
Aren't we supposed to believe in reform?
I thought you'd be
more sympathetic to the victims.
Just forget it.
Reform.
-That hurt.
-Come on.
-Hey.
-There you go.
Shoot!
-Stop!
-That's good!
-Nice shot!
-Pass!
-Hey!
-Here!
-Good!
-Nice!
Hey!
Make a shot!
Yes!
That's a foul!
(PANTING)
MALE REPORTER: Kim, the unprovoked
attacker near Seonpo Station,
showed up at the victim's house again
right after the warrant for his arrest
was rejected,
and was punished by the Vigilante.
He just came and started to beat me.
I didn't do anything wrong,
but he kept saying I should repent.
What are the police doing
when he's bullying innocent citizens?
That shameless bastard.
Next is the victim of
the unprovoked attack near Seonpo Station.
I'm not sure
if he helped us
or if they just got into a fight.
Well... In any case...
VICTIM MS. A
...thank you.
Thank you.
We survived thanks to you.
I'm sure you've heard the saying
that the law is not made for victims.
These complaints have continued
to accumulate
and now, someone has taken the law
into their own hands.
Vigilante.
It refers to a group of citizens
who arm themselves to undertake the law.
How shall we accept
this mysterious vigilante...
SEONWOOK: I knew this would happen.
If I wasn't a police officer,
I'd crush them, too.
Wouldn't you, Jiyong?
He's a hero. A dark hero.
I hope he keeps doing it.
Hey, this is a police university.
Watch your mouth.
Fine.
THANK YOU, VIGILANTE
(SNORING)
VIGILANTE
THE VIGILANTE. GOOD OR EVIL?
"The Vigilante..."
-(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
-(DOOR OPENS)
I'm listening.
Sir, the broadcast was a hit.
We're getting a lot of feedback.
We must plan a follow-up show soon.
-As soon as possible.
-Sure, let's do that. We should.
I told you it was a scoop.
So what's next?
There's a follow-up, right?
Another common point in these cases.
The incidents only take place on weekends.
Don't worry and just trust me.
Something will happen this week, too.
(SOFTLY) Hooray!
I'm late.
I uploaded all the new case files
from the National Police Agency
on the server.
Can you guys categorize them?
-Yes, sir.
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
DUI PROBATION
"Crossing the centerline while DUI..."
ONE DEAD, ONE IN CRITICAL CONDITION...
WOMAN: Get out.
How dare you come here. (CRYING)
How could you even think of coming here?
Leave. Get out.
I'm sorry.
(SOBS) I...
I deserve to die.
-I am so sorry.
-You killed a person.
-You think sorry will cut it?
-I'm sorry.
JIYONG: "Are they...
remorseful?"
MAN: I'm really sorry.
WOMAN: How could a human being do that?
MAN: I'm sorry.
WOMAN: Bring my husband back!
Ms. Choi?
(CLEARS THROAT)
Ms. Choi.
Why still no case? It's already Wednesday.
What about this week's episode?
There's no Vigilante case.
How about we expose
the perpetrator of the Siyoon Case?
Are you crazy?
You think we haven't done that
because we didn't know?
The name of the case is the "Siyoon" Case.
It's named after the victim,
not the perpetrator.
Why should we hide such a man?
How long are we going to
protect the criminal's rights?
Let's do it.
We know who it is because we covered it.
If it becomes a problem,
I'll tell them I did it,
since it's the media's duty to prevent
secondary damage.
The Vigilante will take the bait.
I guarantee it.
(GRUNTS)
"A lot of criminals think
"they've been caught
because of the victims."
(SIGHS)
(CELL PHONE BUZZING)
THE REPO25H BROADCAST HAS STARTED
MALE TV HOST:
These days, faces and personal information
of felons such as serial killers
are often revealed.
However, in the past,
felons were rarely disclosed
for human rights reasons.
The Siyoon Case from 2015 is one of them.
Jeong, a man in his 40s,
committed a terrible crime
against a student at an amusement park,
and was sentenced to only seven years
in prison, claiming temporary insanity.
We will not call this case
the "Siyoon" Case anymore.
The victim had to change her name
because of this.
After much consideration,
REPO25h has decided to disclose
the identity of the criminal.
The name of the child sex offender is
Jeong Deokheung.
That's him.
He was released a few days ago
and is already living
and breathing among us.
Jeong, in his 40s...
What's with you?
I thought you weren't interested.
How could I not be interested?
I'm a cop, too.
(SIGHS)
That's so unlike you, punk.
(GRUNTS)
CHILD SEX OFFENDER
SHOULD BE SENTENCED TO DEATH
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
REPORTER: Back when Jeong was
sentenced to just seven years in prison
for what he'd done to Siyoon,
people were dissatisfied
with the punishment.
Police officers have been dispatched
after receiving complaints,
but there are too many protesters
for them to control.
Come out, Jeong Deokheung!
Let me see your face!
Guys, I'll smash his head.
You sons of bitches!
Keep it down! I couldn't sleep a wink
because of you!
That bastard is a Deokheung sympathizer?
Is he Deokheung's real brother?
Were you even interested
when the victim's family protested?
The house prices will drop
because of this. Get lost!
-...it's elastic and fits perfectly...
-(GLASS SHATTERS)
Those bastards.
...gives you nice volume.
It is fancy...
MANAGER KWAK: (SIGHS) You think
it'll be all right?
What do you mean?
It's more intense that I expected.
What if someone kills Jeong Deokheung
before the Vigilante punishes him?
Then...
... they become a vigilante, too.
(KEYPAD BEEPING)
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
KOREA CRIMINAL DATABASE
SELECT FILE
SIYOON'S CASE
CRIME SCENE INVESTIGATION REPORT
CRIME SCENE PHOTOS
(DOOR OPENS)
Hey.
You're early.
Yes, I still have some
categorization work left to do, so...
Is that so?
(CLEARS THROAT)
(DOOR OPENS)
Why didn't you turn on the lights?
Right.
Let me see.
What?
It's almost done already.
You're working too hard on it.
I mean, it's just a club activity to you.
It's not like I'm paying you.
Don't say that, sir.
I'm just honored to be helping you
with your profiling app.
(SCOFFS)
-Anyway, Jiyong.
-Yes?
That won't get you good grades.
-You know that, right?
-Yes.
(FOOTSTEPS RECEDING)
FUCK OFF, SEX OFFENDER
AGAINST JEONG DEOKHEUNG'S RELEASE
DIE, JEONG DEOKHEUNG
(WOMAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY ON TV)
(CAR ENGINE STARTS)
(CAR HONKS)
(TIRES SCREECH)
(CARS HONKING)
(PANTS)
(CAR HONKS)
-Captain.
-Yes?
Take a look at this.
JEONG DEOKHEUNG
What?
Is Deokheung from China? A Korean-Chinese?
No, he's Korean.
God, I can't believe this bastard.
Captain, Deokheung's electronic
anklet signal was cut off at Incheon Port.
Could he be trying to stow away?
Since everyone knows him in Korea.
-Detective Woo.
-Yes.
Request the Coast Guard for cooperation
and check the stow-away points.
And you two, go keep an eye on the victim.
-Remember it's confidential.
-Yes, sir.
(CROWD CLAMORING)
What's the point of tightening security?
You lost the criminal
and made the citizens more anxious.
Do your job properly
and stop wasting tax money.
This is why...
Let's go.
The key to preventing retaliatory crimes
is thorough punishment of perpetrators
and protection of victims.
But there are many cases
where the victim's information is...
JEONG VANISHED OVERNIGHT
...leaked to the perpetrator these days.
And it causes...
It's causing more subsequent crimes.
What could be the reason?
Kim Jiyong.
-Kim Jiyong.
-Jiyong.
Yes, sir.
Can you tell us?
Well...
I think it's because
many criminals think they were caught
because of the victims.
It seems they put the blame on the victim,
rationalize their behavior,
and commit crimes again.
(BELL CHIMING)
All right. Have a good weekend.
See you next week.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(SEAGULLS SQUAWKING)
Okay.
(CAR APPROACHING)
Did you get anything?
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
They might get all the credit.
(SIGHS)
Set up the camera. Let's at least
capture Deokheung getting caught.
Yes, sir.
We can't film the police capturing him.
That's not what the public wants to see.
A video of the Vigilante
crushing and punishing the criminals!
That's what we need to film
to hit big. Okay?
Why are you yelling? It's easier said
than done. How will we do it?
I'm just trying to get
the next best thing. Got another plan?
-Look.
-Yeah, that's him.
JEONG DEOKHEUNG! STOWED AWAY FROM INCHEON?
EXPRESS BUS TO INCHEON
What?
God damn it.
All right. I understand.
God damn it. I got it.
He must have dumped his anklet in the sea.
It's tracked to the ocean.
We checked all the ships that left today,
but nothing's come up.
And these are the ships
scheduled to leave tonight.
Why are there so many ships?
How will we investigate all of them?
-What if he's already fled?
-(SIGHS)
Request additional guards from
the Coast Guard and tell Jo to join them.
Yes, sir.
Where did this bastard go?
Yes.
Yes, sir. I'll come down right now.
Okay.
(SIGHS) What a mess.
What did they say?
They want us to come to Incheon.
They're short-handed.
-Let's go, then.
-Hey, wait.
At least one of us should stay.
You stay here.
Okay.
-See you later.
-See you.
-Stay safe.
-You too.
Excuse me. Wait.
Could you pull up your visor?
I'm with the police.
Could you pull up the visor?
I want to see your face.
What for?
Never mind.
Thank you for your cooperation.
You can go.
AUTOMATED VOICE: Doors closing.
Bucheon.
Gwangmyeong.
Ansan.
Suheung.
KIM SIYOON CHILD RAPE CASE
Donggye-dong, Suheung...
(ELEVATOR CHIMES)
Sir! Jeong Deokheung isn't
trying to stow away.
We have to get to Siyoon's house
in Suheung! Now!
-Hey! To Suheung!
-To Suheung!
(CAR HONKING)
Aren't they REPO25h
who first reported about Deokheung?
They seem to be in a hurry.
It's weird, right?
Let's follow them. Let's go!
God damn it.
(POLICE SIREN WAILING)
(YAWNS)
Where is it for?
Unit 716.
Someone ordered food
for those guarding it.
That wasn't necessary.
(YELPS)
Put down the knife.
Put it down, or I'll smash your head.
-Now.
-You shit.
(GRUNTS)
Who are you? Who the hell are you?
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMS, GROANS IN PAIN)
(GROANING)
Jeong Deokheung, you son of a bitch!
(SCREAMS)
(GROANING)
(YELPING)
You son of a bitch. You piece of shit.
What's going...
(YELLS)
Let go of me! Let go of me.
Go! Run!
Now! Hurry.
(GROANING)
Hey!
(PANTING)
(SCREAMS)
Siyoon.
Everything's ruined because of you.
(BREATH TREMBLING)
What are you talking about?
You completely ruined my life, you bitch.
(WHIMPERING)
Why is that my fault?
I'm the victim. Why?
I should've fucking killed you back then.
Then none of this would've happened.
The whole world is
pointing the finger at me
-and cussing me out. Damn it!
-(GASPS, WHIMPERS)
So I'm going to kill you now
and live the rest of my life
comfortably in prison.
(SCREAMS)
(DEOKHEUNG GROANING)
Shit.
(GROANING)
You should've lived
the rest of your life repenting.
What are you talking about, you shit?
Resent the law that freed you.
What the fuck are you talking about,
you bastard?
(GRUNTS)
You son of a bitch!
(SCREAMING IN PAIN)
(WHIMPERING) Please!
(GROANS)
(WEAKLY) Please, don't kill me.
-Do you want to live?
-Yes...
Then write an apology letter.
A sincere one.
I will.
I will do it.
(BRAKES SCREECH)
(CAR HONKS)
Get out of the way!
(TIRES SCREECH)
(SIRENS WAILING)
You can't come in.
But I live in this apartment.
I'm sorry.
-Be careful.
-Yes, sir.
Watch out for the stairs.
Be gentle.
What... What happened?
-Detective Ko.
-God damn it.
Take him to the hospital! Hurry!
Damn it!
-You can't enter.
-My friend is in there.
No, you can't enter.
JIYONG: There is a void in the law.
It is often lenient to bad guys
who don't deserve it.
HEAVEN'S NET
I'M SORRY. FORGIVE
Now...
I will fill that void.
This...
is justice.
(INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)